DERRICK **ZZIWA**

Kampala, Uganda 🙃

+256754893983 📞

derricktab44@gmail.com

✓

linkedin.com/in/derrick-zziwa-68a198136 in

derricktab.github.io



INTRODUCTION

I have used a range of languages, operating systems, and development tools as well as experiencing the system development life cycle. Specializing in artificial intelligence and mobile technology, I am keen to make interesting products in software development.



EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Computer Science | Kabale University

2019 - 2023

Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Web and Mobile Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Simulation and Modelling, Computer Organization and Architecture.

Certificate In Machine Learning | Google AI – Explore ML

MAY 2021 - AUGUST 2021

Computer Vision, TensorFlow, OpenCV, Matplotlib, NumPy.

Certificate In Cyber Security | Cisco Networking Academy

JAN 2021 – JUNE 2021

Encryption, Cryptography, Ethical Hacking.



EXPERIENCE

Mobile App Developer Intern | Y0 Uganda Limited

JAN 2022 - FEB 2022

- ✓ Mobile Application Development
- ✓ Working with Restful APIs
- ✓ Bitbucket Source Control
- ✓ Development of a loan management system

Junior Software Engineer | Tabzilic Technologies

JUNE 2021 – DECEMBER 2021

- ✓ Systems analysis with clients to determine requirements talking to managers and staff and observing work practices throughout the supply chain
- ✓ Analysis of data including modeling
- ✓ Part of a software development team creating a stock control system linking mobile devices to warehouse systems
- ✓ Demonstrating prototypes to staff
- ✓ Field testing, implementation, and evaluation

- ✓ Participating in final project reporting
- ✓ Contributing to English language documentation and training

Web Developer | IBO Associational Group Ltd

DEC 2020 - JUNE 2021

- ✓ Website Development (Html, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, Bootstrap)
- ✓ Web hosting (cPanel)
- ✓ Logo designing

Lab Attendant | Kabale University

SEPT 2019 - SEPT 2020

- ✓ Installing and updating Software on all lab computers.
- ✓ Maintaining the computers in a good working condition.
- ✓ Setting up projectors for lecturers in the lab.



SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, C++, Dart, SQL, PHP and HTML.
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, and Android.
- ♥ Frameworks: Flutter, Bootstrap.
- Technologies: TensorFlow, OpenCV,
 Docker, FastAPI, Firebase, Google Cloud
 Platform, Cloud Firestore.
- Skills.
- Ability to work independently and as part of a wider team.
- Ability to multi-task and stay organized in a dynamic work environment.
- ♦ Ability to pay attention to detail.



ACTIVITIES

- I represented Uganda in the Africa IOT and AI challenge finals which were held in Dubai and we came out 2nd best in Africa.
- I am currently the Google Developer Students Club Lead for Kabale University.
- I am the Principal Investigator for the Malnutrition Digital Assistant Project which is an Al based mobile application for diagnosis of malnutrition in children below 5 years.
- I am working on an autonomous obstacle detection and avoidance robot to deliver drugs in hospitals.
- I am the Research Lead for Youth Mappers, Kabale University Chapter.
- I am also a member of Data Science Africa.
- Member of DevCareer Africa.
- Member of Black In Al
- I am the Technical Lead for the Computing Students Association Kabale University.
- Google Solution Challenge 2020&2021 participant.



REFERENCES

References Available on Request